Inventory of the United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1941-1946
  - American correspondent reports, 1941-1946
    - Broadcast recordings, 1946 March 19 (Record cabinet)
      In part 2, "Filipino X" predicts, to an American reporter, a Filipino revolution in the coming days.
      Other miscellaneous recordings are also on the original disc.
    - Brumby radio report about The Flying Tigers, 1945 March 10 (Record cabinet)
    - Bud Foster and Don Pryor radio reports, 1945 April 16 (Record cabinet)
      Bud Foster reports from Guam on the battle of Okinawa.
      Don Pryor reports from Okinawa on the rumor of victory in Europe.
    - Bud Foster radio report, 1945 April 2 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 351: Foster speaks about the advances of American forces against the Japanese.
    - Bud Foster radio report, 1945 April 13 (Record cabinet)
      Foster reports from Okinawa about American soldiers' reaction to the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt.
    - Bud Foster radio report, 1945 April 13 (Record cabinet)
      Foster reports on the reaction of American soldiers to the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt.
    - Bud Foster radio report, 1945 April 14 (Record cabinet)
      Foster reports from Okinawa on the fight against the Japanese.
    - Bud Foster radio report, 194? February 23 (Record cabinet)
      This report concerns the battles with the Pacific Theater of World War II. Foster reports for the combined American radio networks.
    - Bud Foster radio report, 1945 April 4 (Record cabinet)
      Foster reports about the death of a particular Japanese soldier by two bullets.
    - Bud Foster radio report number 353, 1945 April 2 (Record cabinet)
      Foster reports from the Okinawa Jima in the Ryukyu Islands. An upbeat report, he reports on the success American forces have had in taking territory and dividing the Japanese forces.
      Sound quality is intelligible but not pristine due to poor reception.
    - Bud Foster radio report on the Battle of Iwo Jima, 1945 February 24 (Record cabinet)
      Foster reports from Guam for the Combined American Networks.
    - Bud Foster, Don Pryor, and Norman Paige radio reports, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut (#392), Bud Foster reports from Okinawa on the effect of weather on the fighting in the Pacific.
      In the second cut (#393), Don Pryor reports from Okinawa on the fighting between American and Japanese forces in the Pacific.
      In the third cut (#394), Norman Paige reports from Okinawa on how one can view America's actions in the Pacific.
    - Charles Minor radio report, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Minor reports from Shanghai Harbor on financial matters of China.
    - Charles Minor radio report and King George VI address, 1945 May 8 (Record cabinet)
      Minor reports on the opinions of the common man on recent events: the death of FDR, the United Nations Conference on International Organization, and the American invasion of Japan.
      King George VI gives an address of remembrance for those that gave their life.
      The audio quality is poor due to palmitic acid deterioration of the original recording.
    - Charles Minor radio reports, number 206, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Minor comments on the state of the war and the likely actions of the United States and China.
      Part 2: Minor comments on the advent of peace in the Pacific, especially as it pertains to bombers and bombings. He interviews an American bomber pilot.
    - China's aims for the United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Bob Brumby reports from XGOY about the Chinese delegation to the United Nations Conference on International Organization. He focuses on how while the communists and Kuomintang disagree at home, they will present a united group to the conference.
    - Combined American networks radio reports, 1945 April 1 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 346
    - Don Bell and Charles Minor radio reports, 1945 August 19 (Record cabinet)
      Don Bell reports from Manila for the Mutual Broadcasting System. He covers the surrender of the Japanese to General Willoughby, Japanese rank and file opposition to Allied occupation, and a GI cemetery on a day of prayer.
      Charles Minor interviews Captain Litcomb[sp?] about the flight of Japanese officials to the surrender of World War II.
    - Don Bell and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 August 29 (Record cabinet)
      Don Bell reports from Okinawa on the eve of an American offensive on Japan.
      Jack Mahon reports about the beginning of American occupation of Japan.
    - Don Bell and Paul Manning radio reports, number 647, 1945 August 8 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Bell reports on speculation of how the US will use the atomic bomb on Japan following the dropping on Hiroshima. He says that the only thing known for sure is that it will end the war more quickly than traditional bombs.
      Part 2: Bell reports on U.S. soldiers' reaction to news of the atomic bomb.
      Part 3: Paul Manning examines how the atomic bomb was the wish of Nazi Germany.
    - Don Bell and Susan Tate radio reports, 1945-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Don Bell reports from Tokyo on the lack of liberal reforms in the Japanese government during the American occupation under General MacArthur.
      Susan Tate reports for the American Red Cross.
    - Don Bell and Susan Tate radio reports, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Don Bell reports on 18 August 1945 from Manila on General MacArthur's growing dissatisfaction with Japanese officials and military delays.
      Susan Tate reports for the American Red Cross. She talks to several voters about their mindset following the end of fighting in the Pacific.
    - Don Bell radio report, 1946 April 10 (Record cabinet)
      Bell reports from Tokyo on the election of a new Prime Minister. He predicts that the winner is Ichirō Hatoyama. Describing the election process, he focuses on how various voters of Japan voted.
    - Don Bell radio report, 1945 September 24 (Record cabinet)
      Bell reports from Tokyo about Karuizawa and the Japanese interment of foreigners that occurred there during the war. He describes it as the Casablanca of Japan. He discusses which nationalities received what amount of food rations.
    - Don Bell radio report, 1945 August 25 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 744: Bell reports about children in Japan. He says that Japanese children are no different than others. However, he says foreign children that have lived in wartime Japan are "the most pathetic thing" he's seen, detailing their hardship.
    - Don Bell radio report from Bikini Lagoon, 194? July 24 (Record cabinet)
      Bell reports from Bikini Lagoon for the Mutual Broadcasting System on an underwater atomic bomb test.
    - Don Bell radio report from Japan, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 720: Bell comments on the Mutual Broadcasting System and its journalists' relationship with Radio Tokyo. He describes the relationship as a "war" starting in 1939. He then describes the role of American-controlled Radio Tokyo following the fighting.
    - Don Bell radio report from Manila, 1945 March 17 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 314: Bell reports on the fighting in the Philippines, including, but not limited to, the military conquests and humanitarian work of the U.S. forces.
    - Don Bell radio report from Manila, 1945 August 14 (Record cabinet)
      Bell reports from Manila on the implications of the end of the war. He focuses on the reaction of Manila, American soldiers, and Gen. MacArthur's occupation of Japan.
    - Don Bell radio report from Manila, 1945 August 25 (Record cabinet)
      Bell reports, first, about the rebuilding and spirit of Manila following the end of the war and, second, the pending invasion of Japan.
    - Don Bell radio report on preparations for the Able test at Bikini Atoll, 1946 June 9 (Record cabinet)
      Bell reports about rehearsals for the first atomic bomb test at Bikini Atoll. He relays comments by General William E. Kepner before giving a general roundup of the preparations. He calls the operations "an excellent show."
      There are two cuts on the original disc. The first one was crossed out with wax markings, and thus has extra poor quality in part 1.
    - Don Bell radio reports, 1946 May 24-June 7 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Bell reports from the USS Mt. McKinley en route to Bikini for Operation Crossroads. He concentrates on safety measures taken to prevent radiation poisoning.
      Part 2: Bell explores the likely size of the Able explosion.
      Part 3: Bell reports on Admiral Blandy's expectations for the atomic tests following additional information from previous explosions.
      Part 4: Bell reports on 7 June 1946 about the third atomic bomb test at Bikini Island set for early 1947.
      Part 5: Bell reports on the natives of the Marshall Islands' opinions on nuclear weapons, nuclear energy, and international organization.
      Part 6: Bell reports on the evacuation of natives from areas affected by the Operation Crossroads tests and the decimation of their original island.
    - Don Bell radio reports and official communiqué sound recordings, 1945 July 10 (Record cabinet)
      Side A is undated. Side B gives the date as 10 Jul 1945 in the program.
      Side A ,cut 1: Administrative note
      Side A, cut 2: A Bell
      Side A ,cut 3: B
      Side A, cut 4: C
      Bell reports from Manila about the American fight against Japan.
      Side B, cut 1: Communiqué 420
      Side B, cut 2: Communiqué 421
    - Don Bell radio reports, 1945 November 27 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 782: Bell reports from Tokyo. In the first recording, he talks about pending war crime trials against Japanese officials. In the second recording, he talks about GI vacation spots in Japan. The third and fourth recordings are administrative transmissions not that were not meant for broadcast.
    - Don Bell reports on the Able Day rehearsal, 1946 June 23 (Record cabinet)
      Bell reports on the Operation Crossroads Able Day rehearsal at Bikini Lagoon. He describes the grandeur of the preparations and the excitement in the air.
    - Don Bell, Bob Brumby, and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 August 11 (Record cabinet)
      In part 1, the journalists report on the attempted suicide of Tojo and the American hunt for Japanese war criminals.
      In part 2, Don Bell reports on raising prices in Japan, which he claims is done to stick it to the Americans, and Jack Mahon reports on the Japanese public's opinion of the American invasion and occupation.
    - Don Davis interviews Colonel Boyington sound recording, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Davis interviews Colonel Boyington in San Francisco about technological developments and post-war news.
      Also includes music and Morse code recordings.
    - Don Pryor and Jack Hooley radio reports, 1945 April 12 (Record cabinet)
      Don Pryor reports from Okinawa on 12 April 1945 about the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt and the reaction of American soldiers. Included are thoughts on if the death will affect the war, the following peace, or the United Nations Conference on International Organization.
      Jack Hooley reports from Okinawa on a similar theme.
    - Don Pryor and Norman Page radio reports, 1945 April 13 (Record cabinet)
      Don Pryor and Norman Page report from Okinawa on the reaction of soldiers to the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt.
    - Don Pryor and Norman Paige radio reports, 1945 April 9 (Record cabinet)
      Don Pryor reports from Okinawa on 9 April 1945. He interviews another correspondent on how the American invasion of Okinawa compares to the American invasion of Sicily.
      Norman Paige reports from Okinawa on the planes en route to fronts of the war.
    - Don Pryor interviews Vice Admiral Richmond K. Turner and General Holland Smith, 1945 February 5 (Record cabinet)
      From Guam, Turner and Smith discuss military operations on Iwo Jima.
    - Don Pryor radio broadcast about peoples' attitudes in American occupied Okinawa, 1945 April 12 (Record cabinet)
      Pryor reports off the coast of Okinawa. He talks about his experiences in Simabuku and Awashi and the Japanese people he's observed. He analyzes their mental state from a variety of angles, but returns to the idea that fear is the overriding emotion for the Japanese. It is so bad for some that they were asking American forces to kill them in the tombs of their ancestors. Some still believe the Americans plan to torture, enslave, and/or kill them. He also looks at these people's ties to Pearl Harbor.
    - Don Pryor radio report, 1945 February 28 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 266: Pryor interviews Marine Sergeant Thomas, platoon leader that raised the American flag over Iwo Jima.
      Two cuts of the same program. Sound quality is poor for both, but there is less interference in cut 1.
    - Don Pryor radio report, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 344
    - Don Pryor radio report, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Pryor reports from Okinawa on how the Japanese are fighting back against American advances in the Pacific. He interviews a journalist from Gannett, who saw the front.
    - Don Pryor radio report, 1945 April 6 (Record cabinet)
      Pryor reports about the Battle of Okinawa.
    - Don Pryor radio report, 1945 April 6 (Record cabinet)
      PRIOR POOL 4/6/45 #376 2+ 2'55"
      HONEYMOON ON OKINAWA IS OVER, BATTLE IS ON"
    - Don Pryor radio report number 352, 1945 April 2 (Record cabinet)
      Pryor reports off the coast of Okinawa on the conditions of Japanese farms. He notes they are in extreme poverty, with the technology available being centuries behind the times.
    - Don Pryor radio report, 1945 April 4 (Record cabinet)
      Pryor describes his and other correspondents' trip to the southern front.
    - Don Pryor radio report on the Battle of Okinawa, 1945 April 2 (Record cabinet)
    - Don Pryor radio report on the Battle of Okinawa, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Pryor describes the fighting action over Okinawa, focusing on the aerial aspects.
    - Douglas MacArthur speech before the Filipino legislature and other radio broadcasts, 1945 July 8 (Record cabinet)
      Part 2 of the speech as broadcast by the Mutual Broadcasting System.
      The other brief radio transmissions cover news of fighting in the WWII Asian theater.
    - Douglas MacArthur speech on 4 April and Robert Stewart radio report from 22 April, 1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Douglas MacArthur speech to the Filipino legislature, 1945 July 8 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 603: Douglas MacArthur speaks before a joint session of the Filipino legislature in Manilla.
    - Gene Ryder radio report from Turner's Flagship, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Gene Ryder radio report from Turner's Flagship and Edwards' Guam communiqué, 1945 February 24 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Gene Ryder gives the listener the perspective of a soldier in battle. This cut is undated.
      Part 2: Edwards Guam communiqué about Tokyo attack, incomplete.
    - Gene Ryder, Bud Foster, and Larry Tye radio reports, 1945 February 25 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Recording #255, Gene Ryder
      Part 2: Recording #256, Bud Foster
      Part 3: Larry Tye. This cut is crossed out on the original disc and thus has poor audio quality.
    - George Thorn and Gordon Walker radio reports, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 589
      Part 1: George Thorn interviews participants of a rescue glider flight.
      Part 2: Gordon Walker of the Christian Science Monitor reports on the less exciting, behind-the-scenes, aspects of the Pacific fighting of WWII. He returns the listener to the Mutual Broadcasting System.
      Part 3: Gordon Walker reports from Guam for Eyes West. He outlines the difficulty of supplying the troops in the Pacific theater.
      Part 4: Gordon Walker reports from Guam on the backlog, "icebox" in military jargon, of Japanese targets for the American forces.
    - Gordon Walker and Bob Brumby radio reports, number 607, 1945 July 11 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Gordon Walker reports from Guam.
      Parts 2 and 3: Bob Brumby reports from Chungking.
    - Gordon Walker radio report, 194? July 4 (Record cabinet)
      Walker reports from Okinawa on the soldiers' observation--or more accurately the lack thereof--of Independence Day during World War II.
    - Gordon Walker radio report, 1945 July 9 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 601: Gordon Walker reports from Guam on coming under Japanese fire while making an earlier report. He says the American forces were prepared for such an attack and had set traps into which the Japanese walked.
    - Guam communiqué, 1945 April 7 (Record cabinet)
      An American journalist reads section of a communiqué from Admiral Nimitz.
    - Guam Pool reporting by Cooper, 194? November 4 (Record cabinet)
      9:20 AM transmission of a man describing his actions during battle.
    - Interview with First Sergeant Raymond L. Cummings, 1945 April 20 (Record cabinet)
      Interview with First Sergeant Raymond L. Cummings of Montebello, California on 20 April 1945 in Okinawa. Cummings describes fighting the Japanese in the Pacific.
    - Jack Hooley and Tim Lamert radio reports, 1945 April 20 (Record cabinet)
      Hooley and Lamert separately report on the funeral of Ernie Pyle.
    - Jack Hooley radio report, 1945 April 12 (Record cabinet)
      Hooley reports from Okinawa. He describes the island: its physical, environmental aspects; the activities happening; and its war-torn condition.
    - Jack Hooley radio report number 130, 1944 December 24 (Record cabinet)
      Hooley reports from Guam following Admiral Nimitz's first press conference.
    - Jack Hooley radio reports, circa 1945 April 12-17 (Record cabinet)
      In the first report, Hooley reports about the Japanese defense against American forces.
      In the second report, Hooley comments on Japanese citizens under American occupation.
    - Jack Mahon and Bob Brumby radio reports, 1945 August 6 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, Mahon reports on the liberation of prisoners-of-war. This report is heavily jammed.
      In the second cut, Mahon recalls the train ride to the prisoner-of-war camp. He concentrates on the Japanese citizen's daily way of life. This report is also heavily jammed.
      In the third cut, Bob Brumby reports on the capture of Josef Albert Meisinger.
    - Jack Mahon and Colonel Boyington sound recordings, 1945 September 13 (Record cabinet)
      The first cut on side A is a message from Jack Mahon.
      The second and third cuts, Don Davis awaits the arrival of Colonel Boyington in San Francisco.
      On side B, Jack Mahon speaks about the arrest of the last of the Black Dragon war criminals.
    - Jack Mahon and Don Bell radio reports, 1945 September 27-October 10 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Mahon reports from the USS Iowa on the separation of the Victory Fleet in order to expedite returning soldiers.
      Don Bell reports from Tokyo about the release of political prisoners in Japan, a rally for former political prisoners in Japan, and the stolen fortunes the Japanese collected during the war.
    - Jack Mahon and Gordon Walker radio reports, 194? July 14 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 614: Both reporters talk about American attacks on Japan, especially the coastal city of Kamaichi (sp?).
    - Jack Mahon and Jack Hooley radio reports, 1945 April 18 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon and Hooley separately report on the death of fellow journalist Ernie Pyle.
    - Jack Mahon and Leslie Nichols radio reports, 1945 April 14 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Mahon reports from Guam on what to expect in the Pacific Theater once the American forces resume waging war in the coming days. He recounts recent successes.
      Leslie Nichols, reporting from Okinawa, speaks about the state of the American military following the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt.
    - Jack Mahon and Norman Paige radio reports, 1945 May 4-5 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Jack Mahon reports on 4 May 1945 from Guam about a failed Japanese counterattack on Okinawa.
      Part 2: Norman Paige reports on 5 May 1945 from Okinawa.
    - Jack Mahon interviews Jack Dempsey, 1945 April 12 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon interviews boxing champion Jack Dempsey on what Dempsey is doing for the war effort. It consists mostly of teaching the soldiers boxing. He also comments on what military service is doing to other notable boxers.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 652: Mahon reports from Japan shortly after Russia declared war on Japan. However, Mahon concentrates on reviewing American actions against Japan and provides no context on the Russian action.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, 1945 April 18 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon reports for the Mutual Broadcasting System on an awarding of the medal of honor to Sergeant Irwin and what Irwin did to earn it.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, 1945 August 10 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon reports from Tokyo about edicts of General MacArthur. He focuses on the abolition of the imperial headquarters and on censorship of news in the country.
    - Jack Mahon radio report and test cuts sound recordings, 1945 September 10 (Record cabinet)
      Side 1: Mahon reports on 10 September 1945 on General MacArthur's efforts to round up Japanese war criminals, including Tojo.
      Side 2: Test cuts
    - Jack Mahon radio report and other broadcasts, 1945 August 11 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, less than a week before V-J day, Mahon reports on the thoughts of Admiral Halsey on the end of World War II.
      The second cut is a propaganda program that looks at who was responsible for causing and fighting the war.
      The third cut is a transmission containing music and a program in Spanish.
    - Jack Mahon radio report and test cuts sound recordings, 1945 August 12 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 745
      Side A: Mahon reports from Tokyo on the state and future of the Japanese economy.
      Side B: Test recordings of a reporter discussing international issues sometime during Secretary of State Byrnes' tenure. He focuses on Italian reparations and Molotov's opinions thereon.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, 1945 April 13 (Record cabinet)
    - Jack Mahon radio report and communiqué 434 sound recordings, 1945 July 17 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon reports on the bombardment of Tokyo.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, 1945 April 23 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon interviews the fliers who sank the battleship Yamoto.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, 1945 April 3 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon reports from Guam on the American advances in Okinawa. He says "the real fighting" has yet to come.
    - Jack Mahon radio report from Tokyo, 1945-1946 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, Mahon reports during the American occupation of Japan. He focuses on the state of Japanese propaganda.
      The second cut is an administrative transmission.
      In the third cut, Mahon reports about how the former premier of Japan is now a fugitive.
    - Jack Mahon radio report number 321, 1945 March 24 (Record cabinet)
      Reporting from Guam, Mahon interviews two B-29 pilots about what Iwo Jima means to the American soldier.
    - Jack Mahon radio report number 356, 1945 April 3 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon comments on the search for the location of Japanese forces.
    - Jack Mahon radio report number 507, 1945 May 5 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon reports from Guam for the Red Cross Reporter program presented by the Mutual Broadcasting System. He interviews Lieutenants Lohan and Nielsen.
    - Jack Mahon radio report number 635, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Mahon reports from the 3rd fleet off the coast of Japan.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, 1945 September 23 (Record cabinet)